flipsnack.com 2018-06-24

# Privacy policy - Flipsnack

## Your information is kept safe

Last modified: May 23, 2018

Your privacy is important to us, and our policy is simple: we will collect no personally identifiable information about you when you visit the site unless you choose to provide that information. This Privacy Policy does not describe information collection practices on other sites, including those linked to or from Flipsnack. 

### What information do we collect and why do we collect it?

When you visit our site, we track information including the domain name and the name of the web page from which you entered our site, and how much time you spend on each of our pages. We also collect information such as how many times you click on each web page and the methods by which our site was found. We may also collect IP addresses and website usage information from you when you visit our site via the use of "cookies." (An IP address is a number that is assigned to your device by your Internet Service Provider when you are accessing the Internet.) 

Cookies. A cookie is a small file that is stored on the hard drive of your computer ready for future access when you return to our site. We use cookies to deliver web content specific to you and to keep track of your online order activity. Cookies cannot pass viruses, harm your computer or pass on private information such as an email address without the user's intervention. Cookies contain session identification numbers that allow our systems to recall previous sessions for authentication efforts and assemble information from our gathered data. You can configure your computer's browser to alert you when a site is attempting to send you a cookie and allow you to accept or refuse the cookie. In addition to cookies, we may use small bits of computer code called "one-pixel GIFs," "clear GIFs," or "web beacons" embedded in web pages to monitor website activity. We use this collected electronic data to better design our site. We also collect statistical data on how our Flipsnack is used and the flipbooks created with our Service. 

As you use our platform as a registered user, we also collect other information that will allow us to serve you in a reliable manner. This information includes the IP addresses of the devices you use to login in to our platform, the dates and times of your logins, the dates and times of your purchases. We also use third-party services such as Google Analytics, Hotjar and Intercom in order to track your activity on our website. The information we collect through these third-party services includes your IP address, your device type and Operating System, your Internet browser, your location, the pages on our website you have visited, the actions you’ve performed on these pages (including recordings of your interactions, such as movements, mouse clicks), and also the actions you’ve performed in our online app (such as number of flipbooks you have created, upload and download history). We use such information to better understand your needs and improve our platform accordingly, and also to send you marketing messages that are relevant and match your interests. 

We do not collect nor distribute private data such as credit card numbers. This information is collected and stored on the servers of the payment processors (Stripe, Braintree) in order to enable one-time and recurring payments to us. If you wish to delete this information, you can do that in your account settings. 

If you fill in a contact form or request to download a resource, you may be asked to provide personal data such as, but not limited to, your full name, your email address and your consent to receive marketing communications and materials. We collect and process this kind of personal data for the purpose of providing the desired service or resource, study your interests for marketing purposes or improving our website and platform. 

If you leave comments or replies to comments on our [blog](https://blog.flipsnack.com/), you are required to provide your name, your email address and, optionally, your website URL. We require this personal data in order to ensure that you are a real person and to avoid spam. 

### HOW IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED?

Service Providers  
We use certain trusted third party companies and individuals to help us provide, analyze, and improve the Service (including but not limited to data storage, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, payment processing, and improvement of the Service’s features). These third parties may have access to your information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf and under obligations similar to those in this Privacy Policy. 

As of the date this policy went into effect, we use Amazon Web Services for cloud services and database backup and storage. For more information about AWS please visit [aws.amazon.com](https://aws.amazon.com/)

We also use Intercom for marketing automation purposes, including email communications and messages on our website and platform. Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information related to you, such as your email address, company, job title, social network handles and physical location, to optimize your user experience. For more information, please visit [this page](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy). If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us. 

Third-Party Applications  
If you click on a link on our website and go to another site, you will be subject to that website’s privacy policy. If we conduct business with that website such that we need to exchange personally identifiable information, we will make sure that the business has a privacy policy just as protective as ours. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy statement at any website before submitting any personal information at all. 

Advertising  
We use third-party cookies and so-called “pixels” from third parties that deliver ads online. These cookies and pixels track user behavior and allow the networks to serve you tailored advertising that might be of interest to you based on your use of the Flipsnack site. 

To opt out of Google's use of cookies, please visit the [Google Advertising opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). To opt out of targeted Facebook advertising, please visit [this page](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217). Please note however this does not opt you out of being delivered advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

Business Transfers  
If all or part of the company is sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity, the personal information you have provided to us may be transferred as part of that transaction. However, we will take steps to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner consistent with the provisions of our Policy. Additionally, you will be informed about any business transfer in a timely manner and you will have the option to remove your personal data before it is transferred to another entity. 

Other recipients  
Other than those who act on our behalf and except as explained in this Policy, information you provide on this site will not be transferred to unrelated third parties, unless we have your permission to do so.  
However, please note that personal information provided to this site is subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants or orders.  
We allow you to control the disclosure of your non-public personal information to third parties for the marketing of third-party products and services (i.e., your consent is required for disclosure). We must disclose information, when requested, to comply with court orders or subpoenas. 

### HOW DO WE PROTECT THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT?

Your privacy and the security of your personal information are important to us. We maintain and protect the security of our servers and your personal information. All passwords are non-reversibly encrypted before being saved to the database, to ensure that they (and your personal information) cannot be stolen from us, even in case of a hacking attack. We do not collect any passwords at all for users that are connecting using the Facebook Connect API as well as for those connecting with Google API.  
However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, despite the safeguards in place to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, or to or from our online products or services. You transmit all such information at your own risk. However, once we receive your personal information, we will undertake all commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems. We use industry standard encryption methods to protect your personal data. To secure the information we collect online, prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure only appropriate use of information, we have established appropriate physical, electronic and management safeguards. We require usernames and passwords to access sensitive data. 

### WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We will retain your personal data as long as necessary to provide you with the requested services. Once you have deleted your account, we remove your personal data within 30 days from the account deletion date. 

### HOW DO YOU OPT OUT OF PERSONAL INFORMATION SHARING WITH OUR BUSINESS PARTNERS?

Other than agents who act on our behalf, the information you provide through our site will not be transferred to unrelated third parties unless we have your permission to do so. You can opt out of receiving marketing emails at any time by logging into your account and changing your settings in the My Account - Account Settings - Email options section. We will, however, continue to send you emails with information such as, but not limited to: updates about major changes that may severely affect the way you use the platform, changes in your account status, payment failures and successes, or scheduled server updates when our platform may not function. 

You can delete cookies from your hard drive at any time. You can set your Internet browser so that it will not allow cookies to be stored on your device. This may reduce functionality of Flipsnack and may mean that certain features or content will not be available to you. Further information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your device can be found on [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) under the 'manage cookies' section. Alternatively, you can access further information by going to the help menu within your Internet browser. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics on the Flipsnack website visit [ http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  
We use multiple Google products (like Google Analytics, Google Wallet, DoubleClick Ad Exchange, Google AdWords) throughout our site and in iframe embed codes. Therefore we inform you that Google does collect information on it's own. Here is a link to [Google's Privacy Policy page:](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) where you'll also find more information on how to opt out of being tracked by Google. 

### WHAT HAPPENS WHEN WE UPDATE OUR PRIVACY POLICY?

We may on occasion update our Policy. Your acceptance of any minor changes to this Policy is indicated by your continued use of our Service. If we make any material changes to our Policy, we will post a notice about the change at a prominent location on our site. We encourage you to periodically review our site and this Policy for any changes. 

Questions or comments regarding the site should be sent by e-mail to Flipsnack.com support or by U.S. mail to Smartketer LLC, 156 2nd Street, San Francisco, CA 94105 USA. 

### GDPR

If you are located in the European Union, starting with May 25, 2018 your personal data is protected by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in your relationship with all data controllers, both within and outside the EU. 

The information presented in this section of the Privacy Policy apply only to EU residents. 

If you are a EU resident, you need to be aware that the personal data that we collect about you may be transferred to and processed by recipients that are located outside the European Economic Area, some of which are certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, and some not. We will take all necessary measures to ensure that transfers out of the EEA are adequately protected as required by applicable data protection law. 

We will retain your personal data that we collect as described in the previous sections of this Privacy Policy as long as necessary to provide you with the requested services. Once you delete your Flipsnack account, we will take steps to remove your personal data from our systems within 30 days from the date of the account deletion. This does not apply to the extent needed to comply with legal or regulatory obligations to which Flipsnack is subject (e.g. taxation purposes). 

We may also retain your personal data after the termination of your account to the extent necessary to comply with applicable laws or if we need your personal data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim. To the extent possible, we will restrict the processing of your personal data for such limited purposes after the termination of your account. 

### Your rights regarding your personal data as an EU resident

The right to withdraw your consent. When you sign up with Flipsnack, you implicitly agree to our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy, including to how we collect, process and use your personal data. If at any moment after that you wish to withdraw your consent, you can do that with future effect. If you wish to withdraw your consent regarding the receipt of direct marketing communication via email, you can do that by logging into your account and changing your settings in the My Account - Account Settings - Email options section. If you wish to withdraw your consent regarding the collection of other type of personal data, please email us at [contact@flipsnack.com](mailto:contact@flipsnack.com) with your request and we will get back to you with a solution within 30 days from the date of your email. Please keep in mind, however, that certain personal data is absolutely necessary for us to be able to manage your account, so its deletion may only be possible with the deletion of the account altogether. 

The right to request access to your personal data. You have the right to ask whether or not we collect or process personal data about you, and, if we do, to request access to your personal data. You have the right to find out what personal data we have collected about you, the purpose of the collection and who else we have shared this data with. Your access may be restricted, though, by other people’s rights and interests. 

The right to request rectification of your personal data. At your request, we will rectify inaccurate personal data concerning you within 30 days of your request. You also have the right to ask us to complete personal data about you that is incomplete. 

The right to be forgotten. If you wish to have all your personal data erased from our Service, we can honor that request within 30 days of your account removal. Please note that this request means you will have to delete your existing account and everything else that is stored in your account (flipbooks). 

The right to request restriction of processing. You have the right to obtain from us restriction of processing your personal data. In such case, we will only process your data for certain purposes that are mandatory by law. 

The right to request data portability. At your request, you will receive from us the personal data that we’ve collected about you, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, within 30 days of your request.
